Finding aid to the Doris Silbert papers. CA.MS.01151
Smith College Archives
Doris Silbert papers
1919-1984
Smith College Archives
Silbert, Doris, 1901-1984
CA.MS.01151
1.313 linear feet (2 containers)
Professor of music and dean at Smith College. Contains musical programs, ID cards, correspondence, student notebooks, news clippings, photographs, publications, course notes and memorials from her life.
Conditions Governing Access
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Biographical / Historical
Doris Silbert was born in Buffalo, New York, in 1901 to Herman and Helena (Slonim) Silbert. She graduated from Barnard College in 1923 and joined the Smith music faculty the same year. Silbert earned her M.A. from Smith in 1925. At Smith, Silbert became an accomplished pianist and harpsichordist. She taught art history, and wrote several articles on the subject for the Monthly Musical Record, the Musical Quarterly, and Collier's Yearbook. In 1960, Silbert became dean of the college, a position she held until she returned to teaching in 1965. Silbert retired from Smith in 1967, living several years in Northampton before her death in 1984, after a short illness.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Scope and Contents
Materials include student files, such as notebooks, as well as professional files, which contain correspondence, news clippings, publications, professional photographs, ID cards, musical programs, and course notes. The collection also contains a number of memorials, obituaries, and the program to her memorial service.
Silbert, Doris, 1901-1984; Silbert, Doris, 1901-1984
- Correspondence, 1939-1960 (Box 1018, Folder 1)
- Memorabilia, 1984 (Box 1018, Folder 2)
- News clippings, 1927-1928 (Box 1018, Folder 3)
- News clippings, 1920-1984 (Box 1018, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1960-1969 (Box 1018, Folder 5)
- Publications by others, 1953-1984 (Box 1018, Folder 6)
- Publications by Doris Silbert, 1937-1956 (Box 1018, Folder 7)
- Student notebooks, 1919-1920 (Box 1018, Folder 8)
- Student notebooks – Barnard College Geology, 1920-1921 (Box 1018, Folder 9)
- Student notebooks, 1934 (Box 1018, Folder 10)
- Student notebooks – London, 1937 (Box 1018, Folder 11)
- Student notebooks, no date (Box 1018, Folder 12)
- Student notebooks, no date (Box 1018, Folder 13)
- Professional Activities – Course notes, no date (Box 1018, Folder 14)
- Professional Activities – FESTA at FERRARA, program notes, Renaissance conference, 1964 (Box 1018, Folder 15)
- Professional Activities – FESTA at FERRARA, program notes, Renaissance conference, 1964 (Box 1018, Folder 16)
- Professional Activities – Other, 1984 (Box 1018, Folder 17)
- Retirement, memorials, obits, and estate, 1967-1984 (Box 1018, Folder 18)
- Music for "An Evening of Renaissance Music", October 30, 1953 (Box 1018.1)